export const chapter = "Chapter - 17: Natural Resources : Water ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What percentage of the Earth's surface is covered with water?",
        optionA: "25%",
        optionB: "50%",
        optionC: "75%",
        correctAnswer: "C) 75%",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is another name for Earth due to its abundance of water?",
        optionA: "Green Planet",
        optionB: "Blue Planet",
        optionC: "Red Planet",
        correctAnswer: "B) Blue Planet",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Approximately how much of the Earth's total water is in the form of glaciers and ice-caps?",
        optionA: "Less than 1%",
        optionB: "About 2%",
        optionC: "More than 10%",
        correctAnswer: "B) About 2%",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the process of recycling water through evaporation, condensation, and precipitation called?",
        optionA: "Water purification",
        optionB: "Water rejuvenation",
        optionC: "Water cycle",
        correctAnswer: "C) Water cycle",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Why do we face a scarcity of usable water despite the abundance of water on Earth?",
        optionA: "Because water is not evenly distributed",
        optionB: "Because we pollute more water than we use",
        optionC: "Because water is too expensive to extract",
        correctAnswer: "B) Because we pollute more water than we use",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the main reason for water pollution in the text?",
        optionA: "Natural processes",
        optionB: "Industrial use",
        optionC: "Agricultural use",
        correctAnswer: "B) Industrial use",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which continent is mentioned as having the most important source of over-ground fresh water?",
        optionA: "Africa",
        optionB: "Asia",
        optionC: "North America",
        correctAnswer: "C) North America",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary source of water in South India due to its rocky surface?",
        optionA: "Canals",
        optionB: "Wells and tube-wells",
        optionC: "Rainwater collected in tanks",
        correctAnswer: "C) Rainwater collected in tanks",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the purpose of a multipurpose dam in India?",
        optionA: "To store drinking water",
        optionB: "To control floods",
        optionC: "To generate electricity",
        correctAnswer: "C) To generate electricity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the most essential measure to conserve water mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Building more dams",
        optionB: "Reducing water usage and preventing wastage",
        optionC: "Importing water from other countries",
        correctAnswer: "B) Reducing water usage and preventing wastage",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Water is an important natural resource. Almost ____ of the earth's surface is covered with water.",
        optionA: "25%",
        optionB: "50%",
        optionC: "75%",
        correctAnswer: "C) 75%",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Despite the fact that water is very abundant on the earth, all of it cannot be used, so there is scarcity of usable water. Nearly ____ of total water is in the oceans, but it is saline and cannot be used.",
        optionA: "97%",
        optionB: "10%",
        optionC: "2%",
        correctAnswer: "A) 97%",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The process of recycling water involves evaporation, condensation, and precipitation. First, the water evaporates from water bodies and plants; then it condenses in the form of clouds, and at last, it falls to the ground as rainfall or snowfall. This process is called the ____.",
        optionA: "Water purification",
        optionB: "Water rejuvenation",
        optionC: "Water cycle",
        correctAnswer: "C) Water cycle",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The scarcity of water is mainly due to our _____ of water when we use it and the subsequent release of polluted water back into clean water bodies.",
        optionA: "Preservation",
        optionB: "Pollution",
        optionC: "Protection",
        correctAnswer: "B) Pollution",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In India, several towns are already facing a water crisis, and Chennai has to control usage of water because of ____ scarcity of water.",
        optionA: "Abundant",
        optionB: "Acute",
        optionC: "Predictable",
        correctAnswer: "B) Acute",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The most important source of over-ground fresh water is the ____.",
        optionA: "Lakes",
        optionB: "Rivers",
        optionC: "Oceans",
        correctAnswer: "B) Rivers",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In North India, canals are an important source of irrigation and cover about ____ of the total irrigated area.",
        optionA: "10%",
        optionB: "25%",
        optionC: "33%",
        correctAnswer: "C) 33%",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tube-wells are being dug in a large number to tap groundwater for irrigation, but this has put pressure on the water table leading to ____.",
        optionA: "Overabundance of water",
        optionB: "Climatic hazard",
        optionC: "Flooding",
        correctAnswer: "B) Climatic hazard",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A dam is like a strong wall across a river to check water from flowing. The force of falling water is used to generate electricity, called ____.",
        optionA: "Hydroelectricity",
        optionB: "Geothermal energy",
        optionC: "Solar power",
        correctAnswer: "A) Hydroelectricity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Every drop of water is precious, and it is essential that a combined effort is made to ____ water in every possible way.",
        optionA: "Contaminate",
        optionB: "Conserve",
        optionC: "Wastewater",
        correctAnswer: "B) Conserve",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Water covers about 3/4th of the Earth's surface.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Water scarcity is mainly caused by the lack of available water on Earth.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The process of water recycling involves evaporation, condensation, and precipitation.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Water pollution occurs when we use water for various purposes.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Chennai is facing a water crisis due to an abundant water supply.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Canals are an important source of irrigation in South India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Tube-wells are used to tap groundwater for irrigation.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Dams are primarily used to control floods and prevent electricity generation.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "It is important to conserve water to protect our fresh water resources.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "The majority of Earth's freshwater is stored in the oceans.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
